JERRY CASTANOS

551 West 170th New York NY 10032 Castanosje@aol.com 347-404-4416

OBJECTIVE

13 years military and commercial logistics experience in overseas environments such as; Iraq, Afghanistan, Kuwait, Qatar, U.A.E, and Japan. Founded different startup businesses. Currently hold an Associate of Applied Science in Business Administration. Bachelor's degree in Business Administration in progress. Valid passport, driver license, and updated health records. Top Secret Clearance granted in 2012.

EMPLOYMENT EXPERIENCE

3D Heights - New York Chief Executive Officer

October 2013 to Present

Founded 3D Heights in 2013. Managed strategy, technology roadmap and assure client satisfaction for this leading 3D Printing and educational firm. Developed company business practices and SOPs from ground up to eventual brand recognized company. Recruited, hired, and trained top talent. Created a strong marketing and sales plan in accordance with industry standards.

- Developed comprehensive business plan in which \$450k in investment funding was raised.
- Educated and briefed over 10 schools with over 400 students on the use of Computer Aided Design (CAD) software and 3D Printer technology.
- Developed and implement methods and systems for improving operational efficiencies, and control supply and instrument inventory. This included the procurement, receiving & handling, transportation, storing, accounting and issuing of products.
- Launched high growth technology based 3D printing enterprise offering platforms for hyper local 3D
 Printing services. Received mainstream media visibility (e.g. Fox News, CBS, Daily News, The Street, etc.) and significant local and national awards
- Marketed venture extensively and provided community workshops while securing partnerships with New York City STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) Programs.
- Completed over 500 business transaction within the first year of operations

Army Materiel Command (AMC) 3-401st AFSBn –Afghanistan Logistics Operation Battle Captain

May 2012 - October 2013

Employed by Honeywell within the 3-401 AFSBn Support Operations section. Conducted day to day operations within the SPO updating Senior Military Officers and Civilian Staff. Maintains situation awareness of current operations and reports the current status of operations and significant events to the Operations Officer and other members of the command leadership. Maintains non-secure and secure communications with lower, adjacent, and higher units. Assists the AFSBn in preparing, coordinating, and executing logistical orders as required.

- Track over 200 taskings or other open actions from higher command. Serve as an Action Officer for special project.
- Receives, processes and track Commander Critical Information Reports (CCIR) and Serious Incident Reports (SIR).
- Resourced required equipment and supplies to maintain full spectrum operations without interference in unit capabilities.
- Maintain continual situational awareness of over 3500 personnel and 34 remote locations.
- Process over 50 Operational Needs Statements (ONS) weekly in support of Operations in Regional Command (RC-East, RC-North, and RC-West).

Army Materiel Command (AMC) 2-402nd AFSB -Iraq Reset Logistics Planner/ Briefer

May 2010 - November 2011

Employed by Data Solutions & Technology Incorporation-Iraq Reset Operations section. Travel throughout theater to conduct on-site briefings, conferences, and ROC Drill rehearsals. Provide an overview on ARFORGEN, ARI, and TPE turn in requirements and help ensure that the units are best prepared for success upon mission execution. Using the Logistics Information Warehouse (LIW) and LOGSA to provide technical assistance. Gave guidance to units on property book reconciliation using Theater Property Equipment (TPE) Planner and Automated Reset Management Tool (ARMT). Coordinates equipment layouts and inspections with Communications Electronics Command (CECOM), Tank Automotive Command (TACOM), and Program Manager-Heavy Brigade Combat Team (PMHBCT) agencies.

- Conducts 4 weekly theater-wide 180 day reset briefings to multiple units via Sipr conference line.
- Assisted in planning, coordinating, and managing over 40 United States Forces-Iraq (USF-I) Mobile Redistribution Property Accountability Team (MRPAT) assistance for all redeploying units.
- Coordinate and conduct briefs and reset conferences.
- Prepares and distributes daily, weekly, and monthly data reports throughout USF-I and Continental United States (CONUS) military Organizations.

Army Materiel Command (AMC) 402nd AFSB -Iraq Vehicle Fleet Manager

September 2008 - May 2010

Employed by Honeywell Technical Solutions Inc S-4 Staff. As the Vehicle Fleet Manager I managed the maintenance of 1029 vehicles valued at over 40 million dollars throughout Iraq. Maintain a current database and utilize Property Book Unit Supply- Enhance (PBUSE) and Army War Reserve Deployment System (AWRDS) system showing distribution of assigned non-tactical vehicles. Report vehicle accountability to Multi-National Corp Iraq MNC-I C4. Issue out motor vehicle operator's identification card DA Form 5984-E using (AWRDS). Gave guidance to transportation coordinators on vehicle related matters. Attend weekly and monthly meeting with the 402nd Brigade staff in reference to vehicle usage.

- Wrote three comprehensive White Papers detailing certain vehicle management issue and solutions.
- Process lease request of vehicle through the Regional Contracting Command (RCC).
- Wrote and implemented vehicle-operating procedures and vehicle dispatch policies for the 402nd AFSB.

Army Materiel Command (AMC) 2-401st AFSB BDE-Kuwait Februa Lead Standard Depot Systems Technician (SDS)

February 2008 - September 2008

Employed by ITT Industries systems to the wholesale SDS section. Responsible for the implantation and execution of the Army Reset Induction program within GMASS Kuwait. Report directly to the SDS Supervisor on storage, receiving and shipping data input procedures for the GMASS Supply department. The primary roles included monitoring and maintaining property accountability with-in receiving, issue, turn-in, manage and account for Army stock designated for both retail and wholesale. Duty also included running inquiries for the SDS Supervisor when requested, carrying out daily data reconciliation between SDS and Army War Reserve Deployment System (AWRDS) and utilizing MS Excel and Access queries to obtain information and run reports to resolve logistics issues, accomplish receipt processing (inventory adjustments, equipment receipts, and storage adjustments), generates transaction documents for outbound shipments and forwards documents to the Transportation Section.

- Managed 5 Department of Defense Activity Address Codes (DODAAC) and Routing Identification Codes (RIC) (W920FW=ATY, W91PU0=ABK, W90WMB=A2K, W813X7=BBT, W900GL=ATE)
- Supervise training and operations for 18 employees under the Standard Depot System (SDS)/ Army
 Materiel Command Information Supply System (AMCISS) section within GMASS Kuwait.
- Responsible for property accountability valued over \$1 Billion.

Proficient in the following Regulations: DOD 4000.25-1-M, DOD 4000.25-2-M, DOD 4145.19-R-1, AR 190-11, AR 25-400-2, AR 710-1 AR 710-2, AR 735-5, AR 740-26, DA PAM 710-2-2, and Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) .

July 2006 - July 2007

Employed by ITT Industries Systems wholesale SDS section. Maintain inventory control of Army Preposition Stock property through the use of approved automated property management software, Standard Depot System (SDS) and Federal Logistics Information System (FLIS). Manage the overall accountability, procurement, and shelf life serviceability of all equipment, supplies and materials. Ensured all conditions codes were correct in (SDS). Review, monitor, and validate locations in SDS for positive property control. Responsible for property accountability valued over \$100,000,000. Handled time sensitive reports to ensure they are correct and turned in on time. Process material release orders to other supply depot COUNS and OCOUNS. Establish policies and procedures to improve office productivity. Spot checks work in progress and over views inventories to insure conformance to standards and to maintain the highest standards of workmanship and quality. Validate inbound and outbound equipment for property accountability. Responsible for researching and documenting Inventory Adjustment Reports (IAR) to submit. Maintain all file and records under Army Regulation 25-400-2 Army Record Information System (ARIMS) and in accordance with ITT ISO 9000 standards.

- Involved in preparation for participation in the Army's Supply Excellence Award.
- Ensured time-sheets were updated daily and reviewed prior to submission to the
- manager
- Process reconciliation between SDS and Army War Reserve Deployment System (AWRDS) to ensure both systems match at 100%.

Honored with awards for outstanding supply management and field operations:

ITT Certificate of Appreciation (3)

Army Material Command Certificate of Appreciation (2)

Army Materiel Command (AMC) 402nd AFSB BDE (LOCAP III)-Iraq January 2006 - July 2006 Transportation Movement Control Specialist

Employed by Halliburton KBR LOGCAP III contract in support of the 402nd AFSB mission. Provide movement control support for the surface, air movement of cargo and personnel through the U.S. Military Transportation System. Responsible for receiving, validating and processing all Transportation Movement Requests (TMR) and Air Movement Requests (AMR) for the personnel and equipment transiting, originating and terminating assigned MCT area of responsibility. Coordinates between MCT functions to ensure efficient, timely and cost effective support to the customer. Identifies and troubleshoots problem areas in movement and recommends solutions to management. Works closely with customers to ensure desired movement objectives, priorities and schedules and met and communicated to management. Analyzes work processes and develops matrix for measuring performance. Ensure timely processing of personnel and equipment through four stages of air operations. Ensure proper palletizing of air force pallets, including netting, constraints, cleanliness, weight and balance. Responsible for proper weights and balances of personnel and cargo, to ensure accurate aircraft ACL(s) are not exceeded.

- Extensive qualifications in the planning, development, and leadership of occupational workplace, transportation, and transportation safety programs supporting operations throughout the U.S. And abroad.
- Conducted station safety briefings prior to upload and after download of aircrafts.
- Supported development requirements and Hazardous Materials/DOT/OSHA compliance for supervisors and staff.
- Ensure daily reports are accurate and prompt for higher headquarters submission.
- Inventoried and stored over 1000 RFID tags for the military.

1st BN/ 1st Special Forces Group (SFG) –Japan UNIT SUPPLY SERGEANT E-5

November 2002 - November 2005

Employed by the United States Army Special Operations Command (USASOC). Property Accountability, property control, requesting, receiving, recording, storage, movement, consumption, utilization, maintenance, inventory, security, subcontract control, disposition, turning in organization and installation supplies and equipment, and maintaining hand receipts for Government owned property. Responsible for relief of Responsibility/Liability Statement, found on installations and Financial Liability Investigation of Property. Responsible for property accountability for a Special Forces Battalion value \$30,000,000. Ensured all supporting documentation was filed under the Army Records Information Management System (ARIMS). Ensured all transaction were conducted with a PBUSE generate form. Used all open source internet resources I.E: Fed Log, GTN, Logsa, and Defense Logistics Information Service.

- Spearheaded the operational test, analysis, and review of operating supply support system Property
- Supervised and trained 2 soldiers on best Military logistics practices.
- Conducted and supervised 100% annual inventories, 10% monthly inventories, sensitive items inventories, and special inventories on Property Book Unit Supply Enhanced (PBUSE) to evaluate performance and reliability in 2003 at Okinawa Japan.
- Proficient in the following Regulations: AR 710-1, AR 710-2, AR 735-5, and DA PAM 710-2-1.

EDUCATION

School Name: Kaplan University

Degree: Associate in Business Administration

Training, Skills, Certificates

- SAP Enterprise Resource Planning (ERP) software Supply Chain Management (SCM)
- Army Materiel Command Information Supply System (AMCISS)
- Army War Reserve Deployment System (AWRDS)
- Project Management Program (PMP)
- Lean Six Sigma (Green Belt)
- International Organization for Standardization ISO 9000 Training
- Defense Acquisition University (DAU) Courses
- Ammunition Handling
- Government Purchase Card Approving Official
- Government Purchase Card Holder
- OSHA training
- NBC training
- Material Handling Equipment (MHE) Operator
- Army Mail Handling Course
- Paratrooper Airborne Course

Associations

- The International Society Of Logistics SOLE
- National Property Management Association NPMA

GENERAL INFORMATION

- Born US Citizen
- Current US Driver License
- Current US Passport
- Willing to Travel 100% of the Time

Top Secret Clearance